desperateseller.co.uk 2018-11-03

# Privacy policy | DesperateSeller.co.uk

## Who we are

DesperateSeller.co.uk is committed to protecting our customer's privacy. Please take the time to review this notice which explains what information we collect about you, how we use it, and your rights. "DesperateSeller.co.uk" ("we" "our" "us") is the data controller of the personal data collected via or in connection with www.desperateseller.co.uk and/or www.desperateseller.com and/or any associated website or App (the "Site"). 

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 ("Act"), the data controller is DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd (Company Number 04369782) ("DesperateSeller"). The data processor is Motors.co.uk Limited (company number 05975777) ("Motors") 

**You can contact us at:**  
DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd  
Rowan House  
Hill End Lane  
St. Albans  
Hertfordshire  
AL4 0RA  
United Kingdom 

Or via email: [ enquiries@desperateseller.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@desperateseller.co.uk)

If you wish to contact our Head of Privacy & Data Protection, you can do so by emailing 

[dataprotection@desperateseller.co.uk](mailto:). 

Here at DesperateSeller.co.uk, we are absolutely committed to your privacy. We know that we must earn your trust - and keep it - every time you use the DesperateSeller.co.uk website. To make good on that promise, we continually comply with applicable data protection and privacy laws. Most importantly: 

  * We do not publish your email address on the web site; 
  * You have complete control over any emails that DesperateSeller.co.uk sends you; 
  * We do not share your details with any other company for marketing purposes. 

Our Privacy Policy explains what information we collect, how we use and share it, and the choices you have, including how to access the information we have about you, erasing your information and deleting your account. 

Please note that this Policy may change from time to time and, if it does, the latest version will always be available on the Site. 

This policy together with our terms of use ([https://www.desperatedeller.co.uk/terms-conditions](http://www.desperateseller.co.uk/terms-conditions)) and any other documents referred to therein sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. 

## How The General Data Protection Regulation Applies

**Our Legal Bases For Processing Information**

We collect and use the information we have as described below: 

  * as necessary to fulfill our Terms; 
  * consistent with your consent, which you can revoke at any time; 
  * as necessary to comply with our legal obligations; 
  * occasionally to protect your vital interests, or those of others; 
  * as necessary in the public interest; and
  * as necessary for our (or others') legitimate interests, including our interests in providing an innovative, relevant, safe, and profitable service to our users and partners, unless those interests are overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms that require protection of personal data.

## The personal data do we collect about you 

We collect personal data from you when you provide it to us directly and through your use of the Site. This information may include: 

  * Information you provide to us when you use our Site; 
  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our Site. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use DesperateSeller.co.uk, subscribing to any of our services, posting material, sending messages or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you report an issue or concern in connection with your use of DesperateSeller.co.uk or we have received a complaint or query about you; 
  * Details of transactions you carry out via DesperateSeller.co.uk; 
  * Records of your interactions with us (e.g. if you contact our customer service team, interact with us on social media); 
  * Information collected automatically using cookies and other tracking technologies (e.g. which pages you viewed and whether you clicked on a link in one of our email updates). We may also collect information about the device you use to access our Site; 
  * Details of your visits to DesperateSeller.co.uk including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access; 

## What we use this personal data for 

Depending on how you use our Site, your interactions with us, and the permissions you give us, the purposes for which we use your personal data include: 

  * When you register with through the DesperateSeller.co.uk website. We use this information for the purposes of setting up and administering your account on DesperateSeller.co.uk.
  * When you express interest in a vehicle, such as requesting an appointment to view or test drive the vehicle, we will share your contact details with the dealer so they can contact you to deal with such requests.
  * To manage and respond to any queries or complaints to our customer service team. 
  * To personalise the Site to you and show you content we think you will be most interested in, based on your account information, your purchase history and your browsing activity. 
  * To improve and maintain the Site, and monitor its usage. 
  * For market research, e.g. we may contact you for feedback about our products. 
  * To send you marketing messages and show you targeted advertising, where we have your consent or are otherwise permitted to do so. 
  * For security purposes, to investigate fraud and where necessary to protect ourselves and third parties. 
  * To comply with our legal and regulatory obligations. 

## Grounds on which we process your personal data:

DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd processes your personal information on the following grounds: 

  * **Performance of a contract.** DesperateSeller.co.uk provides a service where we connect buyers and sellers of vehicles. Where you use DesperateSeller.co.uk to buy or sell a vehicle whether as a dealer or private individual, you are entering into a contract with DesperateSeller..co.uk Ltd in relation to the use of our service. We process the personal data collected during the transaction process in order to provide this service by storing and exchanging this data with the buyer and seller.
  * **Consent.** Where we process your personal data for direct marketing purposes, for the purpose of sending such communications for such purposes, is based on us having contained valid opt in consent from you to do so. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time though this does not affect the lawfulness of the processing of your personal information prior to that withdrawal. You can withdraw your consent by contacting us at <http://www.desperateseller.co.uk/contact-us>. 
  * **Legitimate Interests.** Where it is not necessary for us to process personal data for the performance of our contract with you, such as the correspondence logs, then this personal data is processed on the basis of DesperateSeller.co.uk or the third party to whom we provide the data pursuing legitimate business interests. It is in our legitimate interest to maintain audit logs of communications between DesperateSeller.co.uk and buyers and sellers of vehicles via DesperateSeller.co.uk. This is to assist in dispute resolution, for quality monitoring purposes and in order for us to demonstrate the value of our service to our clients. Processing undertaken for any other purpose set out above which has not otherwise been specifically dealt with here is processed on the basis of legitimate interests. It is in the legitimate interests of DesperateSeller.co.uk to understand the activities of those who use our websites or apps, to ensure that activity is being undertaken is legitimate, i.e.it is being undertaken by natural persons instead of bots.

## Marketing 

We love to communicate with our customers and so, depending on your marketing preferences, we may use your personal data to send you marketing messages by email. Some of these messages may be tailored to you, based on your previous browsing or purchase activity, and other information we hold about you. 

If you no longer want to receive marketing communications from us (or would like to opt back in!), you can change your preferences at any time by contacting the DesperateSeller.co.uk Customer Service Team at <http://www.desperateseller.co.uk/contact-us>, clicking on the 'unsubscribe' link in any email, or updating your settings in your account. If you unsubscribe from marketing, please note that we may still contact you with service messages from time to time (e.g. membership queries, and information about your legal rights). 

You may also see ads for our Site on third party websites, including on social media. These ads may be tailored to you using cookies (which track your web activity and enable us to serve advertising to customers who have visited our Site). Where you see an ad on social media, this may be because we have engaged the social network to show ads to our customers, or users who match the demographic profile of our customers. 

## Who we share your personal data with 

We share customers' personal data with third parties in the following circumstances: 

  * Staff of DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd or staff members of those who process personal data on behalf of DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd as set out in this section.
  * Motors.co.uk Limited (company number 05975777). 
  * Dealers from whom you wish to buy a vehicle.
  * With our professional and legal advisors. 
  * With third parties engaged in fraud prevention and detection. 
  * With law enforcement or other governmental authorities, e.g. to report a fraud or in response to a lawful request. 
  * In the event that we sell any business assets, the personal data of our customers may be disclosed to a potential buyer. In this event, we will make reasonable attempts to ensure the buyer will be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy. 
  * Otherwise where we have your consent or are otherwise legally permitted to do so. 

## Your rights 

You have certain rights in respect of your personal data, including the right to access and correct your personal data, portability and request the erasure of your personal data. 

You also have the right to object to your personal data being used for certain purposes, including to send you marketing. See 'Marketing' above, for more details of how to opt-out of marketing. 

We will comply with any requests to exercise your rights in accordance with applicable law. Please be aware, however, that there are a number of limitations to these rights, and there may be circumstances where we are not able to comply with your request. To make any requests regarding your personal data, or if you have any questions or concerns regarding your personal data, you should contact us using the details below. You are also entitled to contact your local supervisory authority for data protection. 

DesperateSeller.co.uk may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites. 

### Your rights in relation to your personal information

You have the following rights in relation to the personal information DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd processes relating to you. Where you exercise these rights, DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd will provide information to you as to what action has been taken, if any, within 30 calendar days of receipt of your request. Where no action has been taken, DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd will explain our reasons why. 

Taking into account the complexity and number of requests, it may take DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd up to 90 calendar days to respond to your request. Where DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd intends to extend the deadline for responding, you will be informed within 30 calendar days of receipt of your request. 

### Right of Access

You have the right to request access to the personal information that DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd hold about you.   

### Rights in relation to inaccurate personal information

Where personal information that DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd holds about you is inaccurate, you have the right to request that those inaccuracies are rectified. Taking into account the purposes for which the personal information is processed, you also have the right to have incomplete personal information about you completed.   

### Right to deletion

In certain limited circumstances, you have the right to request that DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd erase personal information relating to you that DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd holds. This right only applies if any one of the following circumstances applies: 

  * Where DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd no longer require the personal information for the purpose(s) for which it was obtained or otherwise used.
  * Where the processing is based on your consent, that consent has been withdrawn and there is no other legal ground for processing.
  * Where you have exercised your right to object to the processing and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for the processing.
  * Where you have exercised your right to object to the use of your personal information for direct marketing purposes.
  * Where the personal information has been unlawfully processed.
  * Where DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd are required to erase the personal information in order to comply with a legal obligation.

The right does not apply where the processing of your personal information is necessary: 

  * For compliance with a legal obligation requiring DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd to process your personal information or where the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest
  * For the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

### Right to restriction of processing

You have the right to request that DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd restrict the processing of your personal information in the following circumstances: 

  * Where you have contested the accuracy of the personal information. In this case the processing of the personal information will be restricted for a period which enables DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd to verify the accuracy of the personal information in question.
  * Where the processing of the personal information is unlawful and you have objected to the information being erased and have instead requested the restriction of its use.
  * Where DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd no longer needs the personal information for the purposes set out above but you require them for establishing, exercising or defending legal claims.
  * Where you have objected to the processing of your personal information. In this case, processing of your personal information will be restricted pending verification of whether our legitimate grounds for continuing to process your personal information override your grounds for objecting.

Where processing of your personal information is restricted for any of the reasons above DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd will not process it, with the exception of storage, unless: 

  * You have provided your consent,
  * For the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims,
  * For the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person, or
  * For reasons of important public interest.

Where DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd have agreed to restrict the processing of your personal information, we will write to you to inform you that we will be lifting that restriction prior to doing so.   

### Right to data portability

This right only applies in the following circumstances: 

  * Where the personal information in question consists of information you have provided to DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd,
  * Where the grounds for processing the personal information stated in section 2 above are consent, explicit consent or for the performance of a contract or to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, and
  * The processing of the personal information is carried via automated means.

Where this right applies, you have the right to receive your personal information in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format. You also have the right to transmit that information to another data controller or, where possible, directly from DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd to another controller.   

### Right to object to processing

You have the following rights in relation to objecting to the processing of your personal information by DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd: 

  * You have the right to object at any time, on grounds relating to your particular situation, to the processing, and
  * The right to object specifically to the processing of your personal information for direct marketing purposes.

You have the right to object to the processing of your personal information at any time, on grounds relating to your particular situation. This only applies where the grounds for processing are: 

  * The processing is necessary for the purposes of legitimate interests pursued by the data controller or by a third party, or
  * Processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest

###  Right to object to processing for the purposes of direct marketing

You have the right to object specifically to the processing of your personal information for the purposes of direct marketing. If you object to the processing of your personal information in this way, then DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd will no longer process it for that purpose.   

### Rights in relation to automated decision making & profiling

You have the right not to be subjected to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which would legally affect you or significantly affect you. However, this right will not apply if the decision: 

  * Is necessary for the entering into, or performance of, a contract between you and DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd
  * Is authorised by or under any law to which DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd is subject, or
  * Is based on your explicit consent.

### Right to complain to the Information Commissioner's Office

Where you believe that DesperateSeller.co.uk Ltd has failed to properly comply with its obligations in respect of your personal information, including your rights as set out in the section above, you can complain to the Information Commissioner. 

The Information Commissioner's Office address is: 

The Information Commissioner's Office  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF 

You can find more information about their role and how to submit a complaint on their website: www.ico.org.uk. 

## Security 

This Site ensures that data is encrypted when leaving the Site. This process involves the converting of information or data into a code to prevent unauthorised access. Encryption methods such as SSL are utilised to protect customer data when in transit to and from this Site over a secure communications channel. 

Whilst we do everything within our power to ensure that personal data is protected at all times from our Site, we cannot guarantee the security and integrity of the information that has been transmitted to our Site. 

## Children 

Our Site is not intended for, and should not be used by, children under the age of 18. We do not knowingly collect personal data from children under 18. 

## Cookies 

As set out in section 2 above, a cookie is a small piece of data that is sent from our web server to your browser, which is saved on the hard drive of your computer, smartphone or other device. 

A cookie cannot: 

  * Read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites;
  * Damage your system;
  * Run programmes on your computer; or
  * Deliver viruses.

###  Why do we use Cookies?

The cookies used on the Site are broken into five categories and are explained below in this clause 6.1 with options to opt out of all or selected cookies.   

###  Essential Site Cookies

These cookies allow you to use essential features of our Site. The essential features of our Site require the use of certain cookies so that we can remember your postcode and what is in your shortlist whilst you continue to browse our Site and/or navigate to different pages of the Site during your browsing session. We are also able to identify you as being logged in to the Site and ensure that you are able to access the appropriate features on our Site. 

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but, if you prefer, you can change your browser to prevent that or to notify you each time a cookie is set. 

Visiting [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) will provide information on settings within your browser as well as other useful information on cookies. 

Below are links to most used browsers with information for blocking cookies, however, be mindful that if you use multiple browsers you will have to undertake this process on each browser and blocking these essential Site cookies will result in a limited experience of the site: 

  * Google Chrome cookie settings
  * Microsoft Internet Explorer cookie settings
  * Mozilla Firefox cookie settings
  * Safari cookie settings
  * IPhone and iPad cookie settings

### Analytics and Optimisation Cookies

These cookies are used to measure website performance, monitor engagement and run experiments to improve user experience of the Site.   

### How Google products use cookies

For a detailed description of how Google use cookies in advertising visit [Google Privacy Terms page](http://www.google.co.uk/policies/technologies/ads/). Google have given the option for you to opt out of ads that have been served based on your usage of Google products. For further information on how [Google uses data](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/) or to opt out of ads based on your interests visit [Control your Google ads page](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads).   

###  What about Hyperlinks?

The Site may sometimes contain hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third party websites have their own privacy policies (including cookies) and we urge you to review them. They will govern the use of any personal information you submit or which is collected by cookies whilst visiting these websites. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such third party websites is at your own risk.   

###  What about Flash Cookies?

A Flash Cookie is a type of cookie which is collected via Adobe Flash Player, and is a piece of software which you probably have on your device to watch videos or podcasts online. We may use Adobe Flash Player to display video or image content. It may not be possible to block or restrict or block Flash Cookies using your browser settings, however, information on how to control flash play privacy and security settings is available from the Adobe website at: <http://www.adobe.com/products/flashplayer/security>.   

### Who do I contact about Cookies?

## Use of Your Personal Information Submitted to Other Websites

We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other third party websites even if you accessed the third party website using links from the Site or you linked to the Site from a third party website. 

We recommend that you check the policy of each website you visit and contact the owner or operator of such website if you have any concerns or questions. 

## Contact Us 

If you have any queries on any aspect of our Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at <http://www.desperateseller.co.uk/contact-us>.
